# **Bassel ASSI**

### FRONT-END DEVELOPER



Name Bassel ASSI

Email address bassel-assi@live.com

**Phone number** +39 320 1538330

**Address** Reggio Emillia

Website

master--basselassi.netlify.app

LinkedIn linkedin.com/in/basselassi

**Github** github.com/baselasi

## **Profile**

I am an Industrial Engineer pursuing a Master's degree in Process and Material Engineering at Trieste University. My journey into programming began with self-learning, mastering HTML, CSS, and JavaScript. As I dug into front-end development, getting the hang of React and Bootstrap was a key part, making me better at creating dynamic and responsive web applications.

Enrolling in a Reindal programming course expanded my knowledge, culminating in an internship. Where i am currently working towards becoming a full-stack developer, I am gaining practical experience in a real-world software environment.

I am an intelligent, disciplined, and responsible individual with a strong motivation for learning and a natural curiosity that drives my continuous pursuit of knowledge.

## **Employment**

### FRONT-END DEVELOPER/intershipe

Nov 2023 - Present

REINDAL, Reggio nell'Emilia

- Proficiently worked with SVELTE framework to enhance and create new components.
- Utilized POSTMAN for API testing, creating organized collections for efficient testing processes.
- Created API calls to both local servers and Microsoft Azure servers
- Collaborated closely with the backend team to identify and communicate issues, fostering a collaborative development environment.
- Worked on improving app responsiveness, ensuring a seamless user experience across different screen sizes.
- Actively participated in team meetings to discuss and solve complex problems related to project development.
- Collaborated with team members to identify innovative solutions, contributing to a more effective problem-solving process.

Pizza Delivery Jan 2022 - Sep 2023

PIZZA PARINI, Trieste

Waiter Jul 2021 - Jan 2022

HOSTARIA MALCANTON, TRIESTE

Car Salesman Jan 2021 - Jul 2021

REAUTO, Martinengo-Bergamo

## **Skills**

JAVASCRIPT/TYPESCRIPT	••••••
REACT	•••••
SVELTE	••••••
NODE/EXPRESS.JS	•••••
MONGODB	•••••
BOOTSTRAP	••••••
CSS	••••••
POSTMAN	••••••
Education	

## Web developer course

Oct 2023 - Nov 2023

Reindal, Reggio nell'Emilia

I completed a 200-hour front-end development course using SVELTE, offered by REINDAL, a software development company based in Reggio nell'Emilia.

# **Master degree in Process And Material**

Sep 2017 - Present

**Engineering** 

Università degli studi di Trieste, TRIESTE, Trieste, Trieste

## **Bachelor Degree In Industrial Engineering**

Sep 2012 - Jun 2016

Università degli studi di Trieste, TRIESTE, Trieste, Trieste

# **Qualities**

- Problem Solving
- Flexibility
- Team Work
- Stress Resistance

## Languages

Italian	••••••
English	••••••
Arabic	•••••